{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"1108","name":"Flood's Bar & Grill","address":"731 St Antoine St","owner":"Michael C. Byrd","licenseNumber":"035183","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","coords":"-83.04036,42.33455","geojson":{"id":"1108","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.040359477,42.33455265]},"properties":{"name":"Flood's Bar & Grill","owner":"Michael C. Byrd","address":"731 St Antoine St","zipcode":"48226","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"035183","establishmentid":"1108","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"180.0","most_recent_license_date":"5/14/2018"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"4627","name":"Starbucks Blue Cross Blue Shield","address":"600 E Lafayette Ave"},{"establishmentid":"3076","name":"Blue Cross Blue Shield","address":"600 E Lafayette Ave"},{"establishmentid":"4478","name":"Greektown Casino - Josephine's","address":"555 E Lafayette Ave"},{"establishmentid":"5047","name":"Greektown Casino - Banquet Kitchen","address":"555 E Lafayette Ave"},{"establishmentid":"4879","name":"Greektown Casino - GT Cafe","address":"555 E Lafayette Ave"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"44596","inspectionDate":"2018-12-18T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-303.11","violationDescription":"After use as a medium for cooling the exterior surfaces of FOOD, or cooling coils and tubes of EQUIPMENT, ice may not be used as FOOD. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":null,"subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-301.11","violationDescription":"(A) To prevent food contamination FOOD EMPLOYEES shall properly wash their      hands.\r\n(B) FOOD EMPLOYEES may not contact exposed, READY-TO-EAT FOOD with      their bare hands and shall use suitable UTENSILS such as deli tissue,       spatulas, tongs, single-use gloves, or dispensing EQUIPMENT. (P)\r\n(C) FOOD EMPLOYEES shall minimize bare hand and arm contact with exposed     FOOD that is not in a READY-TO-EAT form. (Pf)\r\n\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":null,"subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":null,"subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":null,"subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-501.13","violationDescription":"POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be thawed:  Under refrigeration, or under cool running water (<70° F), or as part of cooking process, and total accumulated time above 41° F, for thawed portions, shall not exceed 4 hours.  Any thawing procedure may be used for immediate service for individual consumers order of READY-TO-EAT foods.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":null,"subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.11","violationDescription":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":null,"subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\r\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\r\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\r\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\r\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\r\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\r\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135° F.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":null,"subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"42545","inspectionDate":"2018-06-06T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"6-501.114","violationDescription":"The PREMISES shall be free of items that are unnecessary to the operation or maintenance of the establishment such as EQUIPMENT that is nonfunctional, no longer used and free of litter.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Unnecessary item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not removed from facility","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the UNNECESSARY ITEMS","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Remove from facility/premises."},{"violationCode":"4-204.112","violationDescription":"(A)  In a mechanically refrigerated or hot FOOD storage unit, the sensor of a TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE shall be located to measure the air temperature in the warmest part of a mechanically refrigerated unit and in the coolest part of a hot FOOD storage unit.\r\n(B)  Cold or hot holding EQUIPMENT used for POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD shall be designed to include and shall be equipped with at least one integral or permanently affixed TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE that is located to allow easy viewing of the device's temperature display (EXCEPT, heat lamps, cold plates, steam tables, or other equipment where it is not practical).\r\n(C)  TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be designed to be easily readable.\r\n(D)  FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES and water TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES on WAREWASHING machines shall have a numerical scale, printed record, or digital readout in increments no greater than 1C or 2F in the intended range of use. (Pf)\r\n\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Thermometer(s)","subItem":"refrigeration","problemDescription":"Broken","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"At the Thermometer(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace."}]},{"inspectionid":"39853","inspectionDate":"2017-09-07T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-101.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be safe, unADULTERATED and honestly presented. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Dishonestly presented","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"At the Past date food","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOK LINE AREA","subLocation":"At the COLD HOLDING TEMPERATURES","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"violationCode":"3-501.14","violationDescription":"(A)  Cooked POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be cooled:\r\n         (1)  Within 2 hours, from 135ºF to 70ºF; and (P) \r\n         (2)  Within 4 hours, from 70ºF to 41ºF or less (P)\r\n(B)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared from ingredients at ambient temperature shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41F or less. (P)\r\n(C)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  received in compliance with LAWS   allowing a temperature above 41ºF during shipment from the supplier shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41ºF or less. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cooked food(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"From 70 degrees f to 41 degrees F for more than 4 hours","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"At the COOLING","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \r\n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\r\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\r\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\r\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\r\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\r\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\r\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Raw animal product(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not separated from each other","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"At the RAW FOOD STORAGE","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Keep separate."},{"violationCode":"3-501.15","violationDescription":"(A) Cooling shall be accomplished in accordance with the time and temperature criteria specified under § 3-501.14 by using one or more of the following methods based on the type of FOOD being cooled:  \r\n   (1) Placing the FOOD in shallow pans; (Pf)\r\n   (2) Separating the FOOD into smaller or thinner portions; (Pf)\r\n   (3) Using rapid cooling EQUIPMENT; (Pf)\r\n   (4) Stirring the FOOD in a container placed in an ice water bath; (Pf)\r\n   (5) Using containers that facilitate heat transfer; (Pf)\r\n   (6) Adding ice as an ingredient; (Pf) or\r\n   (7) Other effective methods. (Pf)  \r\n(B) When placed in cooling or cold holding EQUIPMENT, FOOD containers in which FOOD is being cooled shall be:  \r\n   (1) Arranged in the EQUIPMENT to provide maximum heat transfer through the       container walls; and\r\n   (2) Loosely covered, or uncovered if protected from overhead contamination as          specified under Subparagraph 3-305.11(A)(2), during the cooling period to facilitate    heat transfer from the surface of the FOOD.","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food item(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly","subProblem":"In large container","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"At the COOLING METHODS","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Utilize long, shallow pans."},{"violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\r\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\r\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Plumbing system","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"At the Handsink","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Maintain in good repair"},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \r\n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \r\n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \r\n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \r\n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\r\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \r\n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \r\n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\r\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\r\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\r\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\r\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\r\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"beverage dispensing nozzles","problemDescription":"Not cleaned when contaminated","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"At the Pop Gun","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean properly when contaminated."}]},{"inspectionid":"37655","inspectionDate":"2017-01-17T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 25 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"At the Dishwasher (glass washer)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above."},{"violationCode":"6-301.11","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of 2 adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with a supply of hand cleaning liquid, powder, or bar soap. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Soap","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"BAR","subLocation":"At the Handwashing soap","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment components","subItem":"doors","problemDescription":"Broken","subProblem":"","location":"EQUIPMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace."},{"violationCode":"6-301.14","violationDescription":"A sign or poster that notifies FOOD EMPLOYEES to wash their hands shall be provided at all HANDWASHING SINKS used by FOOD EMPLOYEES and shall be clearly visible to FOOD EMPLOYEES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Handwashing signage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"At the Hand washing signage","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \r\n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \r\n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \r\n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \r\n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\r\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \r\n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \r\n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\r\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\r\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\r\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\r\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\r\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned when contaminated","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"At the Pop gun holsters","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean properly when contaminated."},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the Freezer (2 door)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not clean","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the Floors, walls and ceiling","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean"}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"1108"}}